In the last video, we talked
在上节课的视频中
about the Gaussian distribution. In
我们谈到了高斯分布
this video lets apply that
在本节视频中
to develop an anomaly detection algorithm.
我将应用高斯分布开发异常检测算法
Let's say that we have an
假如说我们有一个无标签的训练集
unlabeled training set of M
共有 m 个训练样本
examples, and each of
并且
these examples is going to
这里的训练集里的每一个样本
be a feature in Rn so
都是 n 维的特征
your training set could be,
因此你的训练集应该是
feature vectors from the last
m 个 n 维的特征构成的样本矩阵
M aircraft engines being manufactured.
比如 m 个飞机引擎产品的样本
Or it could be features from m
或者是
users or something else.
来自 m 个用户或者其它的什么东西
The way we are going to address
现在
anomaly detection, is we are
我们解决异常检测的方法是
going to model p of x
我们要从数据中
from the data sets.
建立一个 p(x) 概率模型
We're going to try to figure out what are high probability features, what
我们要尝试计算出这些哪些特征出现的概率比较高
are lower probability types of features.
哪些特征的概率较低
So, x is a
因此
vector and what we
x 是一个向量
are going to do is model p of
我们要做的事情是
x, as probability of x1,
建立一个 p(x) 的模型 表示 x1 的概率
that is of the first component
这是 x 的第一个组成部分
of x, times the probability
并用它乘以 x2 的概率
of x2, that is the probability
这是第二个特征的概率
of the second feature, times the
然后再乘以
probability of the third
第三个特征的概率
feature, and so on up
一直这样下去
to the probability of the final feature
直到最后一个特征  xn
of Xn.
这里我先空着 最后再来填满
So, how do we
那么
model each of these terms,
我们如何为这些项进行建模呢？
p of X1, p of X2, and so on.
p(x1) p(x2) 等等
What we're going to do,
我们下面要做的
is assume that the feature,
是假定特征 x1
X1, is distributed according
其分布
to a Gaussian distribution, with
服从高斯正态分布
some mean, which you
你也可以
want to write as mu1 and
写出期望 μ1
some variance, which I'm going
以及方差
to write as sigma squared 1,
我用 σ1 的平方表示
and so p of X1 is
这样
going to be a Gaussian
p(x1) 就可以写成
probability distribution, with mean
这样一个高斯分布
mu1 and variance sigma squared 1.
其期望为 μ1 方差为 (σ1)^2
And similarly I'm
同样地
going to assume that X2
我假设 x2
is distributed, Gaussian,
也服从高斯分布
that's what this little tilda stands for,
这里的小波浪线读作"服从"
that means distributed Gaussian
表示它服从高斯分布
with mean mu2 and Sigma
其期望为 μ2
squared 2, so it's distributed according
方差为 (σ2)^2
to a different Gaussian, which has
所以它服从的高斯分布与刚刚那个不同
a different set of parameters, mu2 sigma square 2.
它的期望和方差都不一样
And similarly, you know,
与此类似
X3 is yet another
x3 服从另外一个高斯分布
Gaussian, so this
因此
can have a different mean and
x3 也会有一个不同的期望
a different standard deviation than the
以及一个与其它特征不同的标准差
other features, and so on, up to XN.
直到 xn 都是如此
And so that's my model.
这就是我要说的模型
Just as a side comment for
顺便说一下
those of you that are experts in
对那些擅长统计的同学来说
statistics, it turns out that
实际上
this equation that I just
我刚刚写的式子
wrote out actually corresponds to an
写出来实际上就对应于
independence assumption on the
一个从 x1 到 xn 上的独立的假设
But in practice it turns out
但实际中 结果是
that the algorithm of this fragment, it works just fine,
这些算法的效果都还不错
whether or not these features are
无论这些特征
anywhere close to independent and
是否独立
even if independence assumption doesn't
即使这个独立的假设不成立
hold true this algorithm works just fine.
这个算法的效果也还不错
But in case you don't know
如果你不知道
those terms I just used independence assumptions and so on,
我刚刚提到的独立事件和其它相关内容
don't worry about it.
也不要担心
You'll be able to understand
你将会慢慢有能力去理解
it and implement this algorithm just fine
并且能很好地实现这些算法
and that comment was really meant only for the experts in statistics.
刚才插入的那些内容也不重要
Finally, in order to
最后
wrap this up, let me
做一个总结
take this expression and write it a little bit more compactly.
让我把这些式子写得紧凑点
So, we're going to
我可以把这个式子
write this is a product
写成一个乘积式
from J equals one
从 j=1 到 j=n
of XJ parameterized by
乘积项是 p(xj; μj,  (σj)^2)
mu j comma sigma squared
也就是 n 个概率的乘积
j. So this funny
在这里
symbol here, there is
出现了一个有趣的符号
capital Greek alphabet pi,
希腊字母 Π
that funny symbol there corresponds to
这个有趣的字母表示的是
taking the product of a set of values.
一系列数值的乘积
And so, you're familiar with
同时
the summation notation, so the
你应该对求和符号比较熟悉
sum from i equals one through
从 i=1 到 n 求和
n, of i. This
也就是
means 1 + 2 + 3 plus
1+2+3+...
dot dot dot, up to
直到加到 n
n. Where as this
因此刚才的符号 Π
funny symbol here, this product
正如这个求和符号 ∑ 一样
symbol, right product from i
只是表示从 i 等于1
equals 1 through n
到 n 进行连乘
of i.  Then this
那么
means that, it's just like summation except that we're now multiplying.
这里的 Π 用法一样 只不过表示连乘而不是连加
This becomes 1 times
这就变成了
2 times 3 times up
1×2×3 一直乘到 n
to N. And so using
所以这里用的就是
this product notation, this
这里连乘的符号
product from j equals 1 through n of this expression.
这个表达式表示从等于 j=1 开始一直乘到 j=n
It's just more compact, it's
这样写看起来更紧凑
just shorter way for writing
这样写只是避免了
out this product of
把这个乘积表达式
of all of these terms up there.
的所有项都写出来而已
Since we're are taking these p
因为我们需要把
of x j given mu j
所有的 p(xj; μj,  (σj)^2) 项
comma sigma squared j terms
全部乘起来
and multiplying them together.
同时
And, by the way the problem
顺便要说的是
of estimating this distribution
估计 p(x) 的分布问题
p of x, they're sometimes called
这种问题通常被称为
the problem of density estimation.
密度估计问题
Hence the title of the slide.
正如幻灯片的标题上写的
So putting everything together, here
把所有的结合起来
is our anomaly detection algorithm.
下面便是我们的异常检测算法
The first step is to choose
第一步便是选择特征
features, or come up with
或者是找出一些
features xi that we think
我们认为的具有比较反常样本
might be indicative of anomalous examples.
的特征 xi
So what I mean by that,
我的意思是
is, try to come
我们可以尝试
up with features, so that when there's
找出一些特征
an unusual user in your
这些特征能看出比如
system that may be doing
在你的系统里有一些不同寻常的用户
fraudulent things, or when the
可能可以看出他们的反常或欺诈行为
aircraft engine examples, you know
或者是那个飞机引擎的例子
there's something funny, something strange about one of the aircraft engines.
在飞机的众多引擎里有一个奇怪的引擎
Choose features X I, that
选出这种特征 xi
you think might take on unusually
这个特征可能会
large values, or unusually
呈现一个特别大的数值
small values, for what an
或者特别小的数值
anomalous example might look like.
因为这个看起来本身就有些异常
But more generally, just try
但更为普遍的是
to choose features that describe general
尽可能尝试选择能够
properties of the things that you're collecting data on.
描述数据相关的属性的特征
Next, given a training set,
接下来 给出一组
of M, unlabled examples,
m 个无标签数据构成的训练集
X1 through X M, we
从 x(1) 到 x(m)
then fit the parameters,
我们要拟合出
mu 1 through mu n, and
期望 μ1 到 μn
sigma squared 1 through sigma
以及方差值 (σ1)^2 到 (σn)^2
squared n, and so these
同时
were the formulas similar to
这些公式
the formulas we have
和之前视频里的
in the previous video, that we're
公式是类似的
going to use the estimate
因此 我们便可以
each of these parameters, and just to give
估计这些参数的值
some interpretation, mu J,
我们再说得详细一点
that's my average value of the j feature.
μj 是特征 j 的平均值
Mu j goes in this term p of xj.
因此 μj 对应的模型
which is parametrized by mu J
就是 p(xj; μj,  (σj)^2)
so this says for the
因此
mu J just take the
μj 就相当于
mean over my training
对特征 j 的
set of the values of the j feature.
所有训练集数据取平均值
And, just to mention, that you
同时
do this, you compute these
正如我刚才所讲
formulas for j equals
你需要对 j 从1到n
one through n. So use
计算这些概率值
these formulas to estimate mu
也就是说用这些公式来估计 μ1
1, to estimate mu
再估计 μ2
2, and so on up to
直到 μn
mu n, and similarly for sigma
同样地 对于 σ^2 也一样
squared, and it's also
同时
possible to come up with vectorized versions of these.
用向量化的方法也可以写出来
So if you think of
所以 你可以把
mu as a vector, so mu
你把 μ 假想成一个向量
if is a vector there's mu 1,
那么向量 μ 就有
mu 2, down to mu
μ1 μ2 直到 μn
n, then a vectorized
那么
version of that set
这个公式的向量表示形式
of parameters can be written
就能被写出来
like so sum from 1
μ 的值等于 x(i) 的值
equals one through n xi.
从 i = 1 到 n 求和 再乘以 1/m
So, this formula that I
因此我刚刚写出的公式
just wrote out estimates this
还是用来估计 μ 的值
xi as the feature vectors
其中 x(i) 是一系列特征组成的向量
that estimates mu for all the values of n simultaneously.
同时包含了所有 n 个值
And it's also possible to come
同样地 我们也可以
up with a vectorized formula for
写出估计 (σj^2) 的
estimating sigma squared j. Finally,
向量化的公式
when you're given a new example, so
最后 当给出一个新样本时
when you have a new aircraft engine
比如当有一个新的飞机引擎时
and you want to know is this aircraft engine anomalous.
你想要知道这个飞机引擎是否出现异常
What we need to do is then
我们要做的就是
compute p of x, what's the probability of this new example?
计算出 p(x) 的值来 那么这个案例中的概率是多少呢
So, p of x is equal
我们知道 p(x) 的值
to this product, and
等于这个乘积式
what you implement, what you compute,
你现在
is this formula and
需要用这个公式计算
where over here, this thing
而这一项
here this is just the
就是乘积项
formula for the Gaussian
就是在计算高斯概率
probability, so you compute
所以你需要计算出这一项
this thing, and finally if
然后看看
this probability is very small,
如果这个概率值很小
then you flag this thing as an anomaly.
那么你就将这一项标注为异常
Here's an example of an application of this method.
这就是我们应用这种方法的一个案例
Let's say we have this data
假如说我们有一系列数据
set plotted on the upper left of this slide.
就是在幻灯片左上角绘制的数据集
if you look at this, well, lets look the feature of x1.
让我们看这个特征 x1
If you look at this data set, it
如果你看到这个数据集
looks like on average, the features
你会发现它看起来比较平均
x1 has a mean of about 5
x1 这个特征的均值大约是5
and the standard deviation, if
并且也有一个标准差
you only look at just the x1
如果你只看
values of this data set
数据集中 x1 的值
has the standard deviation of maybe 2.
其标准差可能为2
So that sigma 1 and
所以这一段就是 σ1
looks like x2 the
然后你再来看第二个特征
values of the features as
从纵轴测量的
measured on the vertical axis,
特征 x2
looks like it has an average
看起来其平均值
value of about 3, and
可能是3
a standard deviation of about 1. So if
且其标准差值大约为1
you take this data set and if
如果你使用这个数据集
you estimate mu1, mu2, sigma1,
且如果你估计出 μ1 μ2 σ1 σ2
sigma2, this is what you get.
你就会得到这样的结果
And again, I'm writing sigma here,
再次说明一下 我在这里写的 σ
I'm think about standard deviations, but
表示的是标准差
the formula on the previous 5
但先前的公式里给出的
actually gave the estimates of the squares
实际上可以将这些项的平方(也就是方差)
of theses things, so sigma squared 1 and sigma squared 2.
也即得到的是σ1的平方 σ2的平方
So, just be careful whether
所以你要仔细一点
you are using sigma 1, sigma
注意一下到底在使用σ1 σ2
2, or sigma squared 1 or sigma squared 2.
还是 σ1 σ2 的平方
So, sigma squared 1 of course
所以
would be equal to 4, for
σ1的平方的值当然等于4
example, as the square of 2.
就是 2的平方
And in pictures what p of
在图上
x1 parametrized by mu1 and
以 μ1 σ1^2
sigma squared 1 and p
为参数的 p(x1; μ1,σ1^2)
of x2, parametrized by mu
和以 μ2 σ2 为参数的
2 and sigma squared 2, that
为参数的 p(x2; μ2,σ2^2)
would look like these two distributions over here.
呈现出像这样的两个分布
And, turns out that
实际上
if were to plot of p
如果绘制 p(x) 的图像
of x, right, which
也就是
is the product of these two
这两个概率值的乘积
things, you can actually get
事实上
a surface plot that looks like this.
你会得到一个这样的立体图像
This is a plot of p
这就是
of x, where the height
p(x) 值的图像
above of this, where the
我们可以得出
height of this surface at
具体的某一点
a particular point, so given a
对应的高度值
particular x1 x2
给出一个具体的 x1 和 x2 的值
values of x2 if
假如 x1 等于2
x1 equals 2, x equal 2, that's this point.
x2 也等于2 那么就是这个点
And the height of this 3-D
在3-D表面图上的高度
surface here, that's p
就表示 p(x) 值
of x. So p of x, that is the height
所以 p(x) 就是这个图的高度
of this plot, is
完整地写出来
literally just p of x1
这个 p(x) 的值等于
parametrized by mu 1 sigma
p(x1; μ1,σ1^2)
squared 1, times p
乘以
of x2 parametrized by
p(x2; μ2,σ2^2)
Now, so this is
现在
how we fit the parameters to this data.
我们就知道了如何从数据拟合参数
Let's see if we have a couple of new examples.
让我们看看一些新的样本
Maybe I have a new example there.
假如在这里我们有了一个新样本
Is this an anomaly or not?
我要知道这个样本是否异常
Or, maybe I have a different
或许我还有另一个样本
example, maybe I have a different second example over there.
比如我在这里有第二个新样本
So, is that an anomaly or not?
这个样本又是否异常呢?
They way we do that is, we
要回答这个问题
would set some value for
我们可以先给计算机设某个无穷小的数值
Epsilon, let's say I've chosen
假如我设置的
Epsilon equals 0.02.
无穷小量数值为0.02
I'll say later how we choose Epsilon.
我会在后面讲到如何选取 ε 的值
But let's take this first
不过 我们先看第一个样本
example, let me call this
我们把这个称为
example X1 test.
x(1)test
And let me call the second example
同时
X2 test.
称第二个样本为 x(2)test
What we do is, we
我们现在要做的
then compute p of
是计算 p(x(1)test)
X1 test, so we use
我们用上面这个公式
this formula to compute it and
就能计算出来
this looks like a pretty large value.
不难发现这是一个相当大的数
In particular, this is greater
具体地 这个值可能大于
than, or greater than or equal to epsilon.
或者大于等于 ε 值
And so this is a pretty
相较于计算机的无穷小量 ε
high probability at least bigger
这个数值是比较大的
than epsilon, so we'll say that
所以我们说
X1 test is not an anomaly.
x1 检测的结果是 不是异常
Whereas, if you compute p of
然而 如果你计算 p(x(2)test)
X2 test, well that is just a much smaller value.
会是一个更加小的数
So this is less than
比 ε 还要小很多
epsilon and so we'll say
那么我们会说
that that is indeed an anomaly,
x2 确实是一个异常数值
because it is much smaller than that epsilon that we then chose.
因为那已经远远小于了先前我们定义的 ε 值
And in fact, I'd improve it here.
但事实上 我们也可以对这个方法进行改进
What this is really saying is that, you look through the 3d surface plot.
看这个三维表面图
It's saying that all the
从图上不难发现
values of x1 and x2
在这个图的中间部分的x1 x2
that have a high height
通常都对应于
above the surface, corresponds to
一个比较高的表面值
an a non-anomalous example of an OK or normal example.
预示着非异常样本 或者正常样本
Whereas all the points far out
而在周围边缘的点
here, all the points out
这些桃红色的区域
here, all of those
所有这些区域
points have very low
对应的概率值
probability, so we are
都是非常小的
going to flag those points
因此我们会标记这些点
as anomalous, and so it's gonna define
为异常样本区域
some region, that maybe looks
所以 我们也许可以
like this, so that everything
定义某个区域
outside this, it flags
像这样 在这个外面的
as anomalous,
标记为异常区域
whereas the things inside this
而在这个里面的
ellipse I just drew, if it
可以标记为非异常区
considers okay, or non-anomalous, not anomalous examples.
表示无异常的样本
And so this example x2
所以这个测试样本
test lies outside
x(2)test 处于无异常区之外
that region, and so it
也就是说
has very small probability, and so we consider it an anomalous example.
它所对应的概率值很小 因此认为它是一个异常样本
In this video we talked about how to
在这段视频中
estimate p of x, the probability of
我们介绍了如何拟合 p(x)
x, for the purpose of
也就是 x 的概率值
developing an anomaly detection algorithm.
以开发出一种异常检测算法
And in this video, we also
同时 在这节课中
stepped through an entire process
我们也给出了
of giving data set, we
通过给出的数据集
have, fitting the parameters, doing parameter estimations.
拟合参数 进行参数估计
We get mu and sigma parameters, and
得到参数 μ 和 σ
then taking new examples and deciding
然后检测新的样本
if the new examples are anomalous or not.
确定新样本是否是异常 这一系列完整的过程
In the next few videos we
在接下来的课程中
will delve deeper into this algorithm,
我们将深入研究这一算法
and talk a bit more
同时更深入地介绍
about how to actually get this to work well.
怎样让算法工作地更加有效 【教育无边界字幕组】翻译：Yuens 校对/审核：所罗门捷列夫